WUN C. CHIOU, JR.

Allen, TX 75013 | www.wunchiou.com

WEB DEVELOPER, DESIGNER, & EDUCATOR

I am a web developer with 10+ years experience designing and implementing websites, creating web graphics and video, and building web apps. I am well versed with modern authoring and scripting languages, content creation tools, management tools, and digital media. With experience in education, I also have excellent communication skills and can bridge the gap between the tech and business worlds. *Technical skills include:*

Web: HTML5, XHTML, CSS3, JavaScript (pure / jQuery), JSON, AJAX, PHP, SQL, LAMP, shell **Apps:** Dreamweaver, Photoshop, Fireworks, Flash, Acrobat, Camtasia, Vim, MS Office

OS: Mac OSX, Linux, Windows XP/7/8, iOS, Android

EDUCATION

M.S. Degree, Chemistry, UCLA, Los Angeles, CA, 2003

Research focus on computational physical chemistry First in my UCLA class to pass 5/5 physical chemistry cumulative exams Recipient of the US Dept. of Education's GAANN Fellowship, for first-year graduate achievement

B.S. Degree, Chemistry, UC BERKELEY, Berkeley, CA, 1998

With coursework and allied subject alignment in computer science

California Clear Teaching Credential, Secondary Chemistry, 2008 - Present

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

HIGH TECH LOS ANGELES CHARTER HIGH SCHOOL (ht-la.org), Los Angeles, CA

Webmaster and Science Teacher, 2004-Present

Instructed 10th – 12th grade students for the top-ranked college preparatory charter high school in CA. Also served as the school's webmaster, designing custom local web tools for students and teachers to use in their projects. Courses taught: *chemistry, environmental science, solar car, statistics, forensics, web programming, web design, advisory.*

- Built a custom student grading web app with a graphical data visualization of student presentation grades, data, and feedback using PHP, AJAX, SQL, and HTML5 canvas tools.
- Designed and managed the school's main website using the Drupal CMS with custom-styled theme utilizing extensive CSS3 and JavaScript/jQuery for fluid and aesthetic user experience.
- Implemented and managed a locally-hosted course management system (Moodle).
- Managed updates to both the system (via git) and the Linux server.
- Optimized web server and database for heavy concurrent access by 400 students.
- Ran technology professional development workshops and created tutorials for staff and students.
- Designed and implemented many cross-curricular projects. See http://mrchiou.wordpress.com
- Collaborated to fund and create a student-made solar-powered car. See http://ht-la.org/solarcar

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE - CONTINUED

MELIE BIANCO (meliebianco.com), Los Angeles, CA

Web Developer, 2003

Designed and launched a new catalog website for a startup, family-owned handbag and accessory company using dynamic HTML, PHP, and database programming.

- Created easy-to-use backend to update and add new products
- Photographed and included hundreds of handbag products
- Managed domain and web hosting

ABBOTT LABORATORIES, Columbus, OH

Physical Science Summer Intern, 1996 – 1996

Performed physical chemistry viscosity measurements for the Ross Products division of Abbott Laboratories. Studied physical characteristics of various products.

- Implemented an intranet publication of data sets from a database using HTML and VBScript.

PACIFIC MICROELECTRONICS/NETUSA.com, Mountain View, CA

Web Design Summer Intern, 1991 – 1995

Designed and developed complete web sites for clients at the dawn of the commercial Internet. Created covers for retail packaging of software products using Corel Draw.

References and work portfolio available upon request.